Mikalai Parafeniuk. Software developer.

October 24, 2019

Contact Information

- Email physmatman@gmail.com
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=177491081
- GitHub https://github.com/ParafeniukMikalaj
- **Phone** +49 179 727 3617, +375 25 754 6119
- Languages English C1, German B2, Russian and Belorussian native speaker
- Location Karlsruhe, Germany

Abstract

I am a software developer with passion for challenging projects, which involve complex distributed systems, algorithms, high load, big data. My main specialization is development of complex backend systems. I mostly worked with Java and its ecosystem, but I am open and keen to learn new technologies if they better suit the project needs. I have a CS bachelor's degree from Faculty of Computer Network and Systems of BSUIR and CS degree from Yandex school of data analysis.

Work experience

Tipico. Since September 2018

Tipico is the leading betting provider in Germany, and I work as a backend engineer in team responsible for financial transactions. Our main goal is to support reliable money handling for company business needs.

Wallet service We work on creating new service to handle all money transaction within Tipico, namelly Wallet Service. This includes capturing all existing use cases inside monolithic application with nearly 900 000 lines of code and moving it to the separate micro service in a safe way.

Key words: huge legacy project, microservices migration, Java 6, Jboss 4, EJB 3.0, Java 12, Reactor, Kubernetes, Jenkins

Mintdata. November 2014 - August 2018

Mintdata started as a consulting company back in 2012, but grown into product company during the next years. I have participated in external projects and in development of internal products as well. I worked at MintData as backend engineer. But due to quite small team I gained lots of experience in different fields: architecture, planning, frontend development, DevOps, communication with customers.

Mintdata platform This project started as an alternative to Apache Storm. Platform was used for different kind of tasks: web crawling, ETL, IoT, operational data analysis. Platform includes a big tool set to build applications, run and deploy them, control performance and execution process. I was responsible for: remote code execution and monitoring, production infrastructure, messaging protocols, REST services.

Key words: Java 8, RabbitMQ, Jersey, ElasticSearch, MySQL, Spring for DI, AWS, Kubernetes, Terraform.

Greenwave IoT platform During 1 year project duration, our team developed a cloud services which handled indications from millions of sensors, allow users to control their devices and create complex scenarios for them. We were a part of distributed team, with colleagues in USA, Switzerland, Singapore. At the end of the project I have performed 2 week on-site training of colleagues in Singapore.

Key technologies: Java 8, Kafka, Cassandra, ZooKeeper, XMPP, Mesos, Docker, Makefile.

Motifinvesting This is a financial project, that allows users to spend their money on creation of investment profiles, which distribute their money in different proportions between different stocks. We have developed a module responsible for observation of market situation and notification of users in case of significant events like price change of their investment profiles.

Key words: Apache Storm, Thomson Reuters, Quotemedia, MySQL, ZooKeeper, Hazelcast.

Yandex. June 2013 - November 2014

I worked at Yandex as Android developer. I have developed common authorization and registration module for all mobile applications. As Yandex has dozens of mobile development teams, I was required to solve complex backward compatibility and synchronization problems and to provide comprehensive documentation for other teams. Key words library development, backward compatibility, Android.

Omegasoftware January 2012 – June 2013

I worked at OmegaSoftware as Web developer. I have created a number of different web sites: site for media company for improvement of advertising planning, site for corporate networks in Germany, site for russian community of builders. Key technologies: Java, Play, Spring, MySQL, Asp.Net, MS SQL, Windows Azure, DevExpress, Oracle DB, Javascript, jQuery, ExtJs.

AndersenSoft July 2011 – December 2011

I have worked at AndersenSoft as Android developer on audiobooks application.

Education

BSUIR 2009-2014 bachelors CS degree. University gave me strong math and programming background. At university I developed several interesting projects like cross-platform guitar tuner, RSA implementation, 1000 card game for Android, several sites and lots of programming assignments.

Yandex school of data analysis 2012-2014 CS degree. This school improved my math and algorithms knowledge and gave me an opportunity to work with machine learning, natural language processing, parallel programming. There I completed a lot of interesting tasks: statistical translator, machine learning competitions at kaggle, lamdas on C++03, named entity recognition, OpenMP, MPI, Wikipedia Page Rank on MapReduce and a lot of others.

Other achievements

GSOC 2012 I have successfully participated in Google Summer Of Code students program in Apache organization in 2012. I have implemented sparse matrix-vector multiplication for Hama project

Coursera Quantum computing course

Coursera Machine learning course